<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.kturtle.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">سلحفاتك</name>
  <name xml:lang="bg">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="is">KSkjaldbaka</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਕੇਟੁਰਲਟਲ</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kturtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKTurtlexx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">KTurtle</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">程式設計_KTurtle</name>
  <summary>Educational Programming Environment</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">بيئة برمجية تعليمية</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bg">Образователна среда за програмиране</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bs">Obrazovno programersko okruženje</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Entorn educatiu de programació</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Entorn educatiu de programació</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Vzdělávací programovací prostředí</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Programmierumgebung für den Unterricht</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Εκπαιδευτικό περιβάλλον προγραμματισμού</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Educational Programming Environment</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Medio por Eduka Programado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Entorno de programación educativo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Hariv programmeerimise keskkond</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Programatzeko ingurune hezigarria</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Ohjelmointiympäristö opetuskäyttöön</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Environnement de programmation éducatif</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Ambiente de programación educativo.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Pendidikan Lingkungan Pemrograman</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="is">Kennsluumhverfi fyrir forritun</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Ambiente educativo di programmazione</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">პროგრამირების საგანმანათლებლო გარემო</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">교육 프로그래밍 개발 환경</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Mokomoji programavimo aplinka</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Lehr-Programmsmeed</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Educatieve programmeeromgeving</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Lærerikt programmeringsmiljø</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਵਿਦਿਅਕ ਪਰੋਗਰਾਮਿੰਗ ਇੰਵਾਇਰਨਮੈਂਟ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Edukacyjne środowisko do programowania</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Ambiente de Programação Educacional</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Ambiente de programação educacional</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Mediu de programare educațional</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Среда обучения программированию</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Výukové programovacie prostredie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Okolje za učenje programiranja</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Programmeringsmiljö för utbildning</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Eğitimsel Programlama Ortamı</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Середовище навчання програмуванню</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxEducational Programming Environmentxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">教育编程环境</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">教育程式環境</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KTurtle is an educational programming environment for learning how to program. It provides all programming tools from its user interface. The programming language used is TurtleScript, which is loosely based on Logo. All commands and messages are translated into the user's language. KTurtle features an intuitive syntax highlighting, simple error messages, integrated canvas to make drawings, an integrated help, slow-motion and step execution.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">سلحفاتك هي بيئة برمجة تعليمية لتعلم كيفية البرمجة. توفر جميع أدوات البرمجة من واجهة المستخدم الخاصة به. لغة البرمجة المستخدمة هي سكربت السلحفاة التي تعتمد بشكل فضفاض على لوغو.تتم ترجمة جميع الأوامر والرسائل إلى لغة المستخدم. تتميز سلحفاة ك بإبراز بناء جملة بديهي، ورسائل خطأ بسيطة، ولوحة متكاملة لعمل الرسومات، ومساعدة متكاملة، وحركة بطيئة وتنفيذ خطوة.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bg">Kturtle е образователна среда за програмиране, с нея се учиш да програмираш. Осигурява всички нужни инструменти за програмиране в своя графичен интерфейс. Използваният език за програмиране е TurtleScript, който е основан на езика Logo. Всички команди и съобщения са преведени на езика на потребителя. Kturtle има удобно осветяване на синтаксиса, опростени съобщения за грешки, вградено платно за рисунки, вграден помощник, забавено и постъпково изпълнение на програмите.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">KTurtle je obrazovno programsko okruženje za učenje kako programirati. On pruža sve programske alate iz korisničkog sučelja. ProgramskI jezik koji se koristi je TurtleScript, koji je labavo zasnovan na Logo. Sve naredbe i poruke su prevedene na jezik korisnika. KTurtle ima intuitivno isticanje sintakse, jednostavne poruke o greškama, integrirano platno za crteže, integrisanu pomoć, usporeno kretanje i izvršenje korak po korak.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El KTurtle és un entorn educatiu de programació per a aprendre com programar. Proporciona totes les eines de programació des de la seva interfície d'usuari. El llenguatge de programació utilitzat és el TurtleScript, el qual està basat en certa manera en el Logo. Totes les ordres i missatges estan traduïdes a l'idioma de l'usuari. El KTurtle ofereix un ressaltat de sintaxi intuïtiu, missatges d'error senzills, un llenç integrat per a fer dibuixos, una ajuda integrada, i execució a càmera lenta i per passos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">KTurtle és un entorn educatiu de programació per a aprendre com programar. Proporciona totes les eines de programació des de la seua interfície d'usuari. El llenguatge de programació utilitzat és TurtleScript, el qual està basat en certa manera en Logo. Totes les ordres i missatges estan traduïdes a l'idioma de l'usuari. KTurtle oferix un ressaltat de sintaxi intuïtiu, missatges d'error senzills, un llenç integrat per a fer dibuixos, una ajuda integrada, i execució a càmera lenta i per passos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">KTurtle ist eine Programmierumgebung mit dem Ziel, das Programmieren möglichst einfach zu lernen. Alle Programm-Werkzeuge sind auf der grafischen Benutzeroberfläche vorhanden. Als Programmiersprache wird TurtleScript benutzt, eine Programmiersprache auf der Grundlage von Logo. Alle Befehle und Nachrichten können in dir Sprache des Benutzers übersetzt werden. KTurtle bietet eine intuitive Syntaxhervorhebung, einfache Fehlermeldungen, eine integrierte Zeichenfläche und Hilfe, eine langsame oder schrittweise Ausführung von Befehlen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Το KTurtle είναι ένα εκπαιδευτικό περιβάλλον προγραμματισμού για να μάθετε να προγραμματίζετε. Περιλαμβάνει όλα τα προγραμματιστικά εργαλεία από το περιβάλλον χρήσης. Η γλώσσα προγραμματισμού που χρησιμοποιείται είναι η TurtleScript, η οποία είναι μία ελεύθερη απόδοση της Logo. Όλες οι εντολές και τα μηνύματα μεταφράζονται στη γλώσσα του χρήστη. Το KTurtle περιλαμβάνει μια διαισθητική επισήμανση του συντακτικού, απλά μηνύματα σφάλματος, ενσωματωμένο καμβά για σχεδίαση, ενσωματωμένη βοήθεια, αργή κίνηση και εκτέλεση με βήματα.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">KTurtle is an educational programming environment for learning how to program. It provides all programming tools from its user interface. The programming language used is TurtleScript, which is loosely based on Logo. All commands and messages are translated into the user's language. KTurtle features an intuitive syntax highlighting, simple error messages, integrated canvas to make drawings, an integrated help, slow-motion and step execution.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">KTurtle estas eduka programmedio por lerni kiel programi. Ĝi provizas ĉiujn programajn ilojn el sia uzantinterfaco. La programlingvo uzita estas TurtleScript, kiu estas loze bazita sur Logo. Ĉiuj komandoj kaj mesaĝoj estas tradukitaj en la lingvon de la uzanto. KTurtle prezentas intuician sintaksan reliefigon, simplajn erarmesaĝojn, integran kanvason por fari desegnaĵojn, integran helpon, malrapidan kaj paŝan ruladon.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">KTurtle es un entorno educativo para aprender a programar. Proporciona todas las herramientas de programación en su interfaz. El lenguaje de programación que se utiliza es TurtleScript, que se basa ligeramente en Logo. Todas las órdenes y mensajes se traducen al idioma del usuario. KTurtle incorpora un intuitivo resaltado de sintaxis, sencillos mensajes de error, un lienzo integrado para hacer dibujos, un sistema de ayuda integrado, cámara lenta y ejecución paso por paso.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">KTurtle on hariv programmeerimiskeskkond, mis õpetab programmeerima. See pakub kõiki programmeerimise tööriistu otse graafilise kasutajaliidese vahendusel. Programmeerimiskeelena on kasutusel TurtleScript, mille kaugemaks eellaseks on tuntud Logo keel. Kõik käsud ja teated on tõlgitud õppuri emakeelde. KTurtle tunnusteks on intuitiivne süntaksi esiletõstmine, lihtsad veateated, lõuend joonistuste tegemiseks, lõimitud abimaterjalid, võimalus rakendada aeglast liikumist ja samm-sammulist programmide täitmist.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">KTurtle programatzen ikasteko programatzeko ingurune hezigarri bat da. Programatzeko tresna guztiak bere erabiltzaile interfazean eskaintzen ditu. Erabiltzen duen lengoaia TurtleScript da, hurrutitik Logo-n oinarritua nolabait. Komando eta mezu guztiak erabiltzailearen hizkuntzara itzulita daude. KTurtle-k berarekin dakartza sintaxi nabarmentze intuitibo bat, errore mezu sinpleak, irudiak marrazteko oihal integratua, eta laguntza integratua, kamera geldoa eta urratsez-urrats exekuzioa.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">KTurtle on ohjelmointiympäristö ohjelmointitaidon oppimiseen. Se tarjoaa kaikki ohjelmointityökalut käyttöliittymästään. Ohjelmointikielenä on TurtleScript, joka perustuu väljästi Logoon. Kaikki komennot ja viestit on käännetty käyttäjän kielelle. KTurtlessa on helposti ymmärrettävä syntaksikorostus, yksinkertaiset virheilmoitukset, oma piirtoalue piirtelyyn, yhdistetty avustustoiminto sekä hidastettu tai askelittainen ohjelman suoritus.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">KTurtle est un environnement de programmation éducatif destiné à l'apprentissage de la programmation. Il fournit tous les outils de programmation depuis son interface utilisateur. Le langage utilisé est TurtleScript, librement inspiré de Logo. Toutes les commandes et les messages sont traduits dans la langue de l'utilisateur. KTurtle intègre une mise en évidence de la syntaxe intuitive, des messages d'erreur simple, un tableau intégré pour dessiner, une aide intégrée et des systèmes d'exécution ralentis ou pas-à-pas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">KTurtle é un ambiente de programación educativo para aprender a programar. Fornece todas as ferramentas de programación desde a súa interface de usuario. Úsase a linguaxe de programación TurtleScript, que está inspirada en Logo. Todas as ordes e mensaxes están traducidas ao idioma do usuario. KTurtle goza dun realzado de sintaxe intuitivo, mensaxes de erro simples, un lenzo integrado para debuxar, axuda integrada, e execución a cámara lenta ou paso por paso.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">KTurtle adalah lingkungan pemrograman pendidikan untuk mempelajari cara memrogram. Ini menyediakan semua alat pemprograman dari antarmuka penggunanya. Bahasa pemrograman yang digunakan adalah TurtleScript, yang secara leluasa didasarkan pada Logo. Semua perintah dan pesan diterjemahkan ke dalam bahasa pengguna. KTurtle memiliki fitur penyorotan sintaks yang intuitif, pesan kesalahan sederhana, terintegrasi kanvas untuk membuat gambar,  terintegrasi bantuan, gerak lambat dan pengeksekusian langkah.</p>
    <p xml:lang="is">KSkjaldbaka er kennslu umhverfi í forritun, sem inniheldur öll verkfæri og notendaviðmót til forritunar. Forritunarmálið sem notað er heitir TurtleScript eða Skjaldbökuskrift og er lauslega byggt á Logo-forritunarmálinu. Allar skipanir og villuboð eru þýdd á tungumál notandans. KSkjaldbaka kemur með auðskiljanlegri áherslulitun á samhengi í málskipan, auðskiljanlegum villuboðum, innbyggðum myndfleti til að teikna á, innbyggðri aðstoð og með framvindu í hægagangi eða skref-fyrir-skref.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">KTurtle è un ambiente educativo di programmazione per imparare a programmare. Nella sua interfaccia utente fornisce tutti gli strumenti per la programmazione. Il linguaggio di programmazione usato è TurtleScript, liberamente ispirato da Logo. Tutti i comandi e i messaggi sono tradotti nella lingua dell'utente. KTurtle include un'evidenziazione della sintassi intuitiva, dei messaggi di errore semplici, un'area integrata per il disegno, una guida integrata, un'esecuzione dei comandi rallentata e passo passo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">KTurtle პროგრამირების სასწავლო პროგრამაა. მას პროგრამირების ხელსაწყოებზე წვდომა მისივე ინტერფეისიდან გააჩნია. გამოყენებული პროგრამირების ენაა TurtleScript, რომელიც ლოგოზეა დაფუძნებული. ყველა ბრძანება და შეტყობინება მომხმარებლის ენაზე ითარგმნება. KTurtle-ს გააჩნია ინტუიტიური სინტაქსის გამოკვეთა, მარტივი შეცდომის შეტყობინებები, ჩაშენებული ტილო ნახატებისთვის, ჩაშენებული დახმარება და ნაბიჯ-ნაბიჯ შესრულების მხარდაჭერა.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">KTurtle은 프로그래밍을 익힐 수 있는 교육용 프로그래밍 환경입니다. 사용자 인터페이스 내에서 모든 프로그래밍을 할 수 있습니다. 프로그래밍 언어는 로고(Logo)를 기반으로 하는 TurtleScript입니다. 모든 명령어와 메시지는 사용자의 언어로 번역됩니다. KTurtle은 직관적인 구문 강조, 간단한 오류 메시지, 쉽게 그릴 수 있는 통합된 캔버스, 내장 도움말, 느린 이동 및 단계별 실행을 지원합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">KTurtle is en Lehr-Programmeerümgeven mit de een dat Programmeren lehren kann. All Programmeerwarktüüch laat sik över de Böversiet bruken. De Programmeerspraak is TurtleSkript, wat mehr oder weniger op Logo opbuut. All Befehlen un Narichten sünd in de Brukerspraak, un dat gifft en eenfach Syntax-Rutheven, Fehlermellen, en inbuut Maalflaag för Tekens, inbuut Hülp, un langsam un Enkelschritt-Utföhren.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KTurtle is een educatief programma voor het leren programmeren. In de interface voor de gebruiker zijn alle hulpmiddelen voor het programmeren te vinden. De gebruikte programmeertaal is TurtleScript (schildpad-programmeertaal), dat min of meer is gebaseerd op Logo. Alle opdrachten en berichten zijn vertaald in de taal van de (Nederlandse) gebruiker. KTurtle  heeft een intuïtieve syntaxismarkering, eenvoudige foutmeldingen, een canvas (tekengebied) waarop de tekeningen worden gemaakt, een hulpfunctie, en de programmastappen kunnen langzaam of stap voor stap worden uitgevoerd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">KTurtle er eit pedagogisk programmerings­miljø utforma for dei som vil læra seg å programmera. Det har alle vanlege programmerings­verktøy samla i eitt vindauge. Programmerings­språket brukt er TurtleScript, som er lausleg basert på Logo. Alle kommandoane og meldingane i TurtleScript er tilgjengelege på morsmålet til brukaren. KTurtle har intuitiv kode­fargelegging, lettforståelege feilmeldingar, ei integrert teikneflate for programmatisk teikning, innebygd hjelp og støtte for køyring av skripta i sakte­modus eller steg-for-steg.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KTurtle jest edukacyjnym środowiskiem programistycznym do nauki programowania. Dostarcza wszystkie narzędzia programistyczne z poziomu graficznego układu sterowania. Używany język programowania to TurtleScript, który jest luźno związany z Logo. Wszystkie polecenia i wiadomości są tłumaczone na język użytkownika. KTurtle umożliwia intuicyjne podświetlanie składni, proste wiadomości o błędach, zintegrowane płótno do wykonywania rysunków, zintegrowaną pomoc, wykonywanie w spowolnieniu i krok po kroku.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KTurtle é um ambiente de programação educativo para ensinar a programar. Oferece todas as ferramentas de programação a partir da sua interface de utilizador. A linguagem de programação usada é a TurtleScript, que se baseia de certa forma na Logo. Todos os comandos e mensagens são traduzidos para a língua do utilizador. O KTurtle oferece um realce de sintaxe intuitivo, mensagens de erro simples, uma tela integrada para fazer desenhos, alguma ajuda integrada, câmara lenta e execução passo-a-passo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KTurtle é um ambiente de programação educativo para ensinar a programar. Oferece todas as ferramentas de programação a partir da sua interface de usuário. A linguagem de programação usada é a TurtleScript, que se baseia de certa forma na Logo. Todos os comandos e mensagens são traduzidos para o idioma do usuário. O KTurtle oferece um realce de sintaxe intuitivo, mensagens de erro simples, uma tela integrada para fazer desenhos, uma ajuda integrada, execução em câmera lenta e passo a passo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">KTurtle — это среда обучения программированию. Все инструменты для программирования доступны из графического интерфейса. Используемый язык программирования — TurtleScript, частично основанный на языке Logo.Все команды и сообщения переведены на язык пользователя. KTurtle имеет интуитивно понятную подсветку синтаксиса, простые сообщения об ошибках, встроенную область для рисования, встроенную справку, замедленное и пошаговое выполнение.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KTurtle je výukové programovacie prostredie na výuku základov programovania. Poskytuje programovacie nástroje zo svojho používateľského prostredia. Použitý programovací jazyk je TurtleScript, ktorý je voľne založený na jazyku Logo. Všetky príkazy a správy sú preložené do jazyka používateľa. KTurtle obsahuje intuitívne zvýrazňovanie syntaxe, jednoduché chybové správy, integrované plátno na kreslenie, integrovaného pomocníka, spomalený záznam a vykonávanie krokov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">KTurtle je izobraževalno programsko okolje za učenje programiranja. Vsa programska orodja so na voljo iz njegovega uporabniškega vmesnika. Uporabljen programski jezik je TurtleScript, ki ohlapno temelji na jeziku Logo. Vsi ukazi in sporočila so prevedeni v jezik uporabnika. KTurtle ponuja intuitivno poudarjanje skladnje, preprosta sporočila o napakah, vgrajeno platno za risanje, pomoč, upočasnitev dogajanja in izvajanje po korakih.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kturtle är en utbildningsprogrammeringsmiljö för att lära sig hur man programmerar. Alla programmeringsverktyg är tillgängliga från användargränssnittet. Programspråket som används är Kturtles eget, vilket är löst baserat på Logo. Alla kommandon och meddelanden är översatta till användarens språk. Kturtle innehåller en intuitiv syntaxfärgläggning, enkla felmeddelanden, integrerad duk för att rita på, integrerad hjälp, och långsam eller stegvis körning.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">KTurtle, programlamanın nasıl öğrenileceğini anlatmak için bir programlama eğitimi ortamıdır. Tüm programlama araçlarını, kendi kullanıcı arayüzünden sağlar. Kullanılan programlama dili, kabaca Logo temelli, TurtleScript'tir. Tüm komutlar ve iletiler kullanıcının diline çevrilmiştir. KTurtle, sezgisel sözdizim vurgulama, basit hata iletileri, çizimleri yapmak için tümleşik tuval, tümleşik bir yardım, yavaş hareket etme ve adım yürütme özelliklerine sahiptir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KTurtle — середовище навчання програмуванню. У інтерфейсі програми передбачено усі засоби для програмування. Мовою програмування є TurtleScript, мова, заснована на мові програмування Logo. Усі команди та повідомлення компілятора можна перекласти мовою користувача. У KTurtle передбачено інтуїтивно зрозуміле підсвічування синтаксичних конструкцій, прості для розуміння повідомлення про помилки, інтегроване полотно для малювання, уповільнене та покрокове виконання програм.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKTurtle is an educational programming environment for learning how to program. It provides all programming tools from its user interface. The programming language used is TurtleScript, which is loosely based on Logo. All commands and messages are translated into the user's language. KTurtle features an intuitive syntax highlighting, simple error messages, integrated canvas to make drawings, an integrated help, slow-motion and step execution.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">KTurtle 是一个学习如何编程的教育编程环境。它提供来自其用户界面的所有编程工具。 使用的编程语言是 TurtleScript，它宽松基于标志。 所有命令和消息都被翻译成用户的语言。 KTurtle 有一个直观的语法高亮、简单的错误消息、绘制图的集成画布、综合帮助、慢动作和分步执行。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">KTurtle 是學習如何寫程式的教育環境。它透過使用者介面提供所有的程式工具。它使用的程式語言是基於 Logo 語言發展出來的 TurtleScript。所有的指令與訊息都翻譯成使用者看得懂的語言。KTurtle 有直覺式的語法突顯，簡單的錯誤訊息，整合式的繪圖畫布，整合式的說明，慢動作與單步執行等功能。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://edu.kde.org/kturtle/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kturtle</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.kde.org/?application=kturtle</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.kde.org/community/donations/?app=kturtle&amp;source=appdata</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Programming in KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">البرمجة في سلحفاتك</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">Програмиране с KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Programant en el KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Programant en KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Programování v KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Programmieren in KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Προγραμματισμός με το KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Programming in KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Programante en KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Programando en KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Programmeerimine KTurtle'is</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">KTurtle-(r)ekin programatzea</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Ohjelmointi KTurtlessa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Programmation sur KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Programación con KTurtle.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Pemrograman di KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="is">Forritun í Kskjaldbaka</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Programmare in KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">პროგრამირება KTurtle-ში</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">KTurtle로 프로그래밍</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Programmeren in KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Programmering med KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Programowanie w KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Programação no KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Programando no KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Programare în KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Программирование в KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Programovanie v KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Programiranje s KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Programmera i Kturtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">KTurtle'da Programlama</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Програмування у KTurtle</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxProgramming in KTurtlexx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">在 KTurtle 中编程</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">在 KTurtle 寫程式</caption>
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/kturtle/kturtle.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kturtle</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="23.08.5" date="2024-02-15"/>
    <release version="23.08.4" date="2023-12-07"/>
    <release version="23.08.3" date="2023-11-09"/>
    <release version="23.08.2" date="2023-10-12"/>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <custom>
    <value key="GnomeSoftware::key-colors">[(62, 151, 62), (92, 165, 91)]</value>
  </custom>
</component>
